TUNC MOROVA

+17788141190

♦ Vancouver, Canada

mortunco

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

Python, R

FRAMEWORKS: NumPy, Pandas,

Tidyverse, SQL

SOFT SKILLS: Project Management,

Problem solving, Leadership, Collaboration, Dependability

DATA VISUALISATION: matplotlib,

seaborn, ggplot, Rshiny, Plotly OTHER TECH SKILLS: Git, AWS,

CLI. VSCode. ML (Linear

Regression, Random Forest Regression and Classification),

RstudioServer, Jupyter Lab, Slurm

Awards

President's Academic Excellence Initiative PhD Award University of British Columbia

Faculty of Science Graduate Award University of British Columbia 2019-2022

International Tuition Award University of British Columbia 2019-2022

Shaun Kenneth Gauthier (Shaun G) Scholarship in Cancer Research The Gauthier Family Endowment

NSERC-CREATE Scholarship

2016 Fall Semester Outstanding Teaching Award Koc University

TUBITAK (The Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey) Project Scholarship TUBÍTAK

2015-2018

faraz.hach@ubc.ca

References

Dr. Nathan Lack Principle Investigator (Lack Laboratory)

Vancouver Prostate Centre 2660 Oak St, Vancouver, BC V6H 3Z6, Canada,

Dr. Faraz Hach Principle Investigator (Hach Laboratory)

Vancouver Prostate Centre 2660 Oak St, Vancouver, BC V6H 3Z6, Canada

I am an enthusiastic graduate student with 7 years of field experience in bioinformatics and data science, with an excellent tract record of publications in high impact journals. With my data analysis and visualization skills, I can confidently unravel the mysteries of multi-dimensional datasets. I would like to pursue my career in the field of data science where I can utilize my computational, machine learning and statistical skills to understand the complex nature of big data sets.

Education

University of British Columbia

2019 to Current

PhD Bioinformatics

Joined Hach Laboratory to develop computational algorithms for cancer genomics. Developed streamlined variant calling and single cell analysis pipelines in Snakemake workflow environment. Became proficient in data visualisation, cleaning and wrangling with R (ggplot2/tidyverse) and Python (pandas/numpy/searborn/matplotlib). Wrote and contributed 9 peerreviewed publications in prestigious journals. Mentored new PhD and Masters students.

Koc University

2015 to 2018

MSc Biomedical Science and Engineering 2018

Analyzed International Cancer Genome Consortium (2648 patients) whole genome sequence data to investigate androgen receptor binding site mutations. Utilized slurm, SGE and AWS instances for high performance computing. Developed analysis pipelines to perform analysis of CRISPR-screens, RNA-seg and ChIP-seg data sets. Became proficient in Unix Command line. Implemented computational analysis pipelines in Docker and Singularity containers for reproducibility.

Marmara University

2010 to 2015

BSc Bioengineering 2015

Employment

Collins Laboratory - Vancouver Prostate Centre

Visiting Scholar

Feb. 2022 to Aug. 2022

Led the analysis of prostate cancer xenograft based single cell dataset (>100,000 cells). Developed streamlined computational pipeline for filtration, marker selection and trajectory analysis to decipher prostate cancer plasticity in single cell resolution.

4Global

Aug. 2018 to Sept. 2018 Intern

Obtained hands on experience on SQL queries. Optimized the performance of 4Global database. Conducted code review and user interface testing

Alkan Laboratory - Bilkent University

Visiting Scholar

Ankara, Turkey Sept. 2017 to Jan. 2018

Conducted the first genome assembly of Alburnus tarichi using PacBio Long Reads

Epigenetix Intern

interface forever.

June 2015 to Sept. 2015

Analyzed microarray data sets with custom R scripts. Parted ways with graphical user interface and switched to Linux command line

Publications

Optimized high-throughput screening of non-coding variants identified from genome-wide association studies

2022

2022

2022

Under revision in Nucleic Acids Research. First author. One of the three PhD thesis project publications which I led the experimental design, statistical analysis and wrote the manuscript with Dr. Lack. Developed novel computational method to reconstruct sequencing fragments to increase experimental accuracy.

Genetic determinants of chromatin reveal prostate cancer risk mediated by context-dependent gene regulation.

Nature Genetics. Contributing second author in multi-national collaboration (Harvard/USA, UBC/CAN, NKI, NL). Using my previously published method, (NAR submission). I investigated prostate cancer risk-associated mutations. Analyzed and visualized results from 12 top candidates

EPIKOL, a chromatin-focused CRISPR/Cas9-based screening platform, to identify cancer-specific epigenetic vulnerabilities

Nature Cell death & Disease, Contributing second author, Side-project during PhD degree, Developed analysis methods for processing CRISPR/Cas9-based knockdown screens. Using my streamlined analysis pipeline >50 samples have been processed, analyzed and visualized.

Androgen Receptor-Mediated Transcription in Prostate Cancer

Cells. Co-first author to invitational review article. Covered the recent advancements in Androgen Receptor enhancer literature

Functional mapping of androgen receptor enhancer activity.

2021

Genome Biology. Co-first author. Led the statistical and computational analysis of this work. Gathered existing public datasets and coordinated the collaboration of machine learning section. Conducted Random Forest Classification and Feature Importance analysis on 102 distinct genomic features to understand the grammar of

Epigenetic-focused CRISPR/Cas9 screen identifies ASH2L as a regulator of glioblastoma cell survival

Accepted Cell death and differentiation. Follow-up study that implemented my computational method from (EPIKOL publication).

Androgen receptor-binding sites are highly mutated in prostate cancer.

2020

2022

Nature Communications. First author. Resulting publication of my MSc thesis. Interrogated whole genome sequencing data of 2048 patients from multiple for somatic mutations. Became proficient in fundamental data analysis and genomic skills.

Bromodomain inhibition of the coactivators CBP/EP300 facilitate cellular reprogramming

2019

Nature Chemical Biology. Contributing second author. Side-project during MSc degree. Processed and visualized tabular RNAseq and ChIPseq datasets (25,000-1,000,000 rows for each sample) in the published work.